Guide to the Hervey Allen Papers, 1831-1965 SC.1952.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Manuscripts, 1900-1949; II.
  - Poetry, 1900-1949; 1.
    - Single Titles
      - Single Titles: M (Box 6, Folder 1)
        - Modern Philosopher, 10.
        - Moments, 1922; 11.
        - Montrogan, 12
        - Moon Sonnet, 13.
        - The Mormon Trail, 14.
        - Morning Noon and Night, 15.
        - Mountain Interlude, 16.
        - Mourn, Psyche, Mourn!, 17.
        - The Murmuring River, 1909; 18.
        - Mutability, 1924; 19.
        - [My days and nights I have not idly spent...], 20.
        - My Verdun, 21.
      - Single Titles: N (Box 6, Folder 2)
        - Nightingales are Scarce West of Exeter, 1.
        - Nostalgia, 2.
      - Single Titles: O (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - [O God looks down...], 1.
        - October, 2.
        - An Ode: To be spoken on Memorial Day, 3.
        - Ode in Time of Madness: An Incantation, 1945; 4.
        - An Ode on Mutability, 5.
        - Ode to the Sun (Sol Invictus), 6.
        - Oh, Where, 7.
        - The Old Judge, 1920; 8.
        - Old Meadows, 9.
        - The Old Song, 10.
        - [On a distant view of Oxford Tower...], 11.
        - [On earth the wind as [evict] us death...], 12.
        - [Once they looked and saw a valley...], 13.
        - One of Hells Proverbs: Wash Day, 14.
        - [Only in dreams of morning...], 15.
        - On the Bay, 16.
        - The Oriol, 17.
        - [Out out brief candle, now the...], 18.
        - Overtones, 19.
      - Single Titles: P (Box 6, Folder 4)
        - Palmetto Town, 1.
        - [Panocia], 2.
        - Paris, Mother of Dreams, 3.
        - Part of Angels Song for Christmas Hymn, 4.
        - Passes E.W., 5.
        - Pay Day, 1916; 6.
        - The Pharaoh of Moses, 7.
        - Pines and Cones, 8.
        - The Pirates, 9.
        - Pittsburgh, 10.
        - Poe in Carolina: Alchemy, 11.
        - The Poets Epitaph, 12.
        - The Poor Poet, 13.
        - Portentia, 14.
        - Predicament, 15.
        - Presences, 16.
        - The Priest and the Pirate: The Ballad of Theodosia Burr, 17.
        - A Processional on Christmas Morning, 18.
        - Proem, 19.
        - Profile-axis, 20.
        - Progress, 21.
        - Prologue: Annie's Town Before the Mills Came, 22.
      - Single Titles: Q (Box 6, Folder 5)
        - The Quality of Beauty, 1.
        - Question, 1940; 2.
      - Single Titles: R (Box 6, Folder 6)
        - The Raid on Dun, 1919; 1.
        - The Rain Bell, 2.
        - [Ramses] Worship of the Third [Cataract], 3.
        - Recollect, 4.
        - Relativity, 1922; 5.
        - A Rendezvous with Life, 6.
        - Rennaisance, 7.
        - Reply to Ambush, 8.
        - The Reubens of Brass, 9.
        - Reverie, 10.
        - Rhapsody, 11.
        - Rhetorical result of an Elegy for Amy Lowell, 12.
        - The Rivals, 13.
        - The Road Beyond the Tower, 14.
        - Roadside Epitaph, 15.
        - The Rose in Amber, 16.
      - Single Titles: S (Box 6, Folder 7)
        - The Sacrifice, 1.
        - Saga of Leif the Lucky, 1923; 2.
        - Salt o' the Earth, 1918; 3.
        - Salt Town, 4.
        - The Scandal, 5.
        - The Scissor Grinder, 6.
        - The Sea Bogy, 7.
        - The Seasons: Autumn Invocation, 8.
        - The Seasons: Winter, 9.
        - [See how the light falls...], 10.
        - The Sewees of Sewee Bay, 11.
        - Shadow to Shadow, 12.
        - Silences, 13.
        - The Skull, 14.
        - Sleep, 1909; 15.
        - Sohrab and Rustum, 16.
        - Soldier Poet: To Francis Fowler Hogan, 17.
        - Source, 18.
        - Speak, 19.
        - The Spirit of the Maid, 1919; 20.
        - Spring Authentic, 21.
        - Spring Shadows, 22.
        - Springs Pilgrims, 23.
        - The Stars of God, 24.
        - Sullivan's Island: To E.A.P., 25.
        - Summer Girl, 26.
        - A Summer Idyll, 27.
        - The Sunflower, 28.
        - Sylvan Poor, 1929; 29.
        - Symbols of Symbols, 30.
      - Single Titles: T (Box 6, Folder 8)
        - The Talker, 1.
        - [That's why I sit here now...], 2.
        - That Tiger Cat of Ours, 3.
        - Theodesia Burr: Her Story as Told by an Old Confederate Naval Officer, 4.
        - [There is a [more]...], 5.
        - They Say, 6.
        - They Watch and Wait, 1916; 7.
        - Thou Mother, 8.
        - Three Landscape Moods: High Tide o' Life, 9.
        - Three Lanscape Moods: Youth, 10.
        - Tiger Lilies, 11.
        - To a Certain Imagist, 12.
        - To a Frozen Butterfly, 13.
        - To a Portrait of Theodosia Burr, 14.
        - To Arthur in Avalon, 1932; 15.
        - To Harriette, 16.
        - To James Whitcomb Riley, 1916; 17.
        - To Ma, 1909; 18.
        - To My Dog, 19.
        - To My Grandparents on Their Fifty Third Wedding Anniversary, 1910; 20.
        - To My Happy Sister Helen, 21.
        - To My Father, 22.
        - To the Home Folks, 1916; 23.
        - To the Polius, 24.
        - To the Prime Minister, Mr. Churchill: Christmas, 1941; 25.
        - To the Winged Victory of Samothrace, 26.
        - The Tower by Might, 27.
        - The Triumph of Edom: Palestine, 28.
        - Twilight, 1916; 29.
        - Twilight Escape, 30.
        - Two Pages from the Book of the Sea Islands: Shadows, 31.
        - The Two Republics, 32.
        - The Tyrant, 33.
      - Single Titles: U (Box 6, Folder 9)
        - [Up all you sluggish men of peace...], 1910; 1.
        - Upstairs Downstairs, 2.
      - Single Titles: V (Box 6, Folder 10)
        - The Vikings: North - Proem, 1923; 1.
        - The Vikings: Saga of Leif the Lucky, 1923; 2.
        - The Vikings: The Cat Witch, 1923; 3.
        - Village Voices, 4.
        - Voice of Live, 5.
      - Single Titles: W (Box 6, Folder 11)
        - Waitin' and Drillin', 1916; 1.
        - Walk [Broad] Song, 2.
        - War Clouds, 3.
        - The Watchful Waiting, 4.
        - We, 1919; 5.
        - [What sound to catch the thing...], 6.
        - When Shady Avenue was Shady Lane, 1919; 7.
        - [When in the 1920's you began...], 8.
        - [When in the night the [manifest] if island must...], 9.
        - [When dwell and life [sit there]...], 10.
        - [When the frost is on the [fancy kin]...], 11.
        - Where the Sugar and Maple Grows, 12.
        - The Wind, 13.
        - The Wingless Victory, 1920; 14.
        - [With life that hurtles like a spark...], 15.
      - Single Titles: Y (Box 6, Folder 12)
        - Yes, 1.
        - YS, 2.
      - Single Titles: Z (Box 6, Folder 13)
        - Zachias, 1946; 1.
    - Major Poems and Collections
      - Black Roses: Original Manuscript (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Black Roses: Photograph (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - The Blindman: Original Manuscript and Correspondence, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 3)
        Correspondence includes editorial conversations Allen had with Amy Lowell. Allen sent early drafts of The Blindman to Lowell who was influential in getting the manuscript published in the North American Review. In her September 12, 1919 letter to Allen she identifies that Allen had "improved [the poem] immensely" and talks about sending it to a "Mr. Sedgwick," most likely Atlantic Monthly's editor at the time, Ellery Sedgwick. The letter ends on a humorous note with Lowell stating Mr. Sedgwick does not know a poem from a potato, but sometimes his taste betrays him and he gets something good by mistake.
      - The Blindman: First and Second Proof (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Carolina Chansons: Preface (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Carolina Chansons: Original Draft and Revisions, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Carolina Chansons: Typed Copies (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Christmas Epithalamium: Original Manuscript (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Children of Earth (from Earth Moods) (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Earth Moods: Original Manuscript (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Flowers from Fields Aflame: Typewritten, 1917-1918 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - The Leaping Poll: Original Manuscript (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Mine Host: Original Manuscript, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - New Legends: Magazine Publications List (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - New Legends: Holograph Manuscript (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - New Legends: Poetic Attitude Holograph and Typed Manuscript (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Saga Leif the Lucky: Preface (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Saga Leif the Lucky: Original Manuscript (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Saga Leif the Lucky and Other Poems, The Vikings: Typescript Manuscript, ca. 1925 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Sarah Simon: Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Sarah Simon: Holograph Manuscript (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Sarah Simon: Typed Manuscript (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Sidonian Hanno: Original Manuscript, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Songs for Annette: Preface (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Selected Poems: Typed White Manuscript (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Other Authors' Works
      - Poems Written by Various Authors (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Prose, 1917-1949; 2.
    This subseries includes bound and loose-leaf handwritten and typewritten drafts, proofs, prefaces, and related correspondence to the pre-publication of Hervey Allen's prose, including various iterative drafts of his novels, short stories, and non-fiction material.
    - Biographies, Novels, and Short Stories
      This group includes handwritten, typewritten, original and various drafts and associated material of Hervey Allen's pre-published biographies, novels and short stories. Material is arranged in alphabetical, chronological, and when possible, in iterative order.
      Box 187-188, Series X: Oversized Material for oversized galleys of particular manuscript titles in this subseries.
      - Action at Aquila: Time Scheme, Character List, and Various Drafts, 1934-1938 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Action at Aquila: Various Drafts of Chapters, Correspondence, Time Scheme, and Outline, 1935-1937 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Action at Aquila: First Holograph Draft, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Action at Aquila: Prospectus, Historical Background, and Sources, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Action at Aquila: Incomplete Typewritten Manuscript with Edits (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Action at Aquila: Original [Incomplete] Typed Manuscript (Chapters 1-16) (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Action at Aquila: Edited Typed Manuscript of Final Version (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Action at Aquila: Setting Manuscript for Printer, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Action at Aquila: Typed White Carbon (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Anthony Adverse: Various Preface Drafts and Syllabus of a Novel to be Called Anthony Adverse, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Anthony Adverse: Preface, Author's Introduction to Limited Edition (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Anthony Adverse: Preface/Author's Statement, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Anthony Adverse: Preface, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Anthony Adverse: Preface, Author's Introduction to Edition, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Anthony Adverse: Synopses, Research Materials, and Notes (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Anthony Adverse: Correspondence, Notes, Drafts of Chapters, and Map of New Orleans in 1815, 1932-1933 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Anthony Adverse: Correspondence, Dedication, and Other Various Material, 1935-1937 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Anthony Adverse: Partial First Handwritten Draft (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Anthony Adverse: Original Typescript, Volume I, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Anthony Adverse: Original Typescript, Volume II, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Anthony Adverse: Original Typescript, Volume III, 1933 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Anthony Adverse: Bound Typescript Draft, Volume I (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Anthony Adverse: Bound Typescript Draft, Volume II (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Anthony Adverse: Bound Typescript Volume III (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Bedford Village: Holograph Manuscript (The Disinherited, Book II) (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Bedford Village: Yellow Typed Manuscript (The Disinherited, Book II) (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Bedford Village: Cut Version with Changes (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Bedford Village: Announcement and Notes (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - The City and the Dawn: Holograph Manuscript, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - The City and the Dawn: First Typed Draft (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - The City and the Dawn: Typed Copy of the Final Holograph Pages (1-50) (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - The Disinherited: Holograph Manuscript of Synopsis and Notes (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - The Disinherited: Synopsis and Notes, 1942 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - The Disinherited: Research Notes and Clippings, Copy of 1744 Treaty, Appendix (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - The Disinherited: Time Scheme and Historical Notes (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - The Forest and the Fort: Holograph Manuscript Book I, 1942 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - The Forest and the Fort: Holograph Manuscript II (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - The Forest and the Fort: Holograph Manuscript III, 1940 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - The Forest and the Fort: Cut Version with Changes (The Disinherited, Book I), 1942 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - The Forest and the Fort: Yellow Typed Manuscript (The Disinherited, Book I), 1942 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - The Forest and the Fort: [Incomplete] Typed Manuscript (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Israfel: Research, Correspondence and Cover Material, 1917-1926 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
      - Israfel: Unused Illustrations, 1926 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Israfel: Notes on Poe from Various Sources, 1926 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Israfel: Printed Pages (1-932) (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Israfel: Typed Fragment as it First Began (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Israfel: Handwritten Preface to First Issue and Re-Issue, 1926; 1934 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Israfel: Carbon Copy of Beginning, 1926 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Israfel: Various Sheets and Chapters, Vol. I (Lacks Chapters 10,11,17), 1926 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Israfel: Partial Handwritten and Typewritten Manuscript, 1926 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Israfel: Typed Manuscript, (Chapters 1-11), 1926 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Israfel: [Incomplete] Early Typewritten and Handwritten Draft, 1926 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - It Was Like This: Two Stories of the Great War: Syllabus, Introduction, and Various Drafts, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
      - It Was Like This: Two Stories of the Great War: Handwritten Holograph, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - It Was Like This: Two Stories of the Great War: Typed Manuscript, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - It Was Like This: Two Stories of the Great War: Typed White Carbon (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Richfield Springs: Handwritten Holograph (Notes, General Approach, Outline, Headings), 1935 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Richfield Springs: Handwritten Holograph (p. 85, Chapters 1-4) (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Richfield Springs: Various Versions of Typed Manuscripts (First Typed Manuscript) (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Richfield Springs: Typed Carbon Manuscript (Chapters 1-4) (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Richfield Springs: Typed Draft for Curtis Brown Ltd. (Chapters 1-4) (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Toward the Flame: Original Handwritten Letter from Hervey Allen on Active Duty, Inspiration for Toward the Flame, 1918 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Toward the Flame: [Formally "Targets"], Manuscript, 1925 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Toward the Flame: Typed White Carbon, 1918-1925 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Toward the Flame: Preface to Re-Issued Edition, 1933 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Toward the Morning: Handwritten Partial Drafts, Announcement, Rejected Pages, and Revised Typewritten Drafts (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Toward the Morning: Complete Yellow Typed Manuscript (The Disinherited, Book III), 1945 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Toward the Morning: Holograph Handwritten Manuscript (Chapters 1-17), (The Disinherited, Book III) (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Toward the Morning: Holograph Handwritten Manuscript (Chapters 18-25), (The Disinherited, Book III) (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Toward the Morning: Complete Typed White Carbon Manuscript, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Articles, Essays, and Plays
      - The ABC of Reviewing (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Amy Lowell as a Poet, 1926 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - An Appreciation [To the Notable Library of Major W. Van R. Whithall], 1927 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Anthony Adverse: The Sources of, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - The Arkansas Kookamoosa (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Books as Gifts and Other Things, 1949 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - A Boy's Memory of Bedford Fifty Years Ago (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - Cats versus Dogs; Crossroads; Cupid's Pitcher, [University of Pittsburgh folder] (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - Of Cities (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - Edgar Allan Poe, on the Dictionary of American Biography (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - Felicity Haul: The Story of Old Bermuda, 1931 (Box 32, Folder 11)
      - The First Co-ed: A Ballad of Pitt (Box 32, Folder 12)
      - The Flood: A One Act Play (Box 32, Folder 13)
      - A Golden Century of American Verse, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 14)
      - Harvest and Reapers: An Anthology of American Poetry from 1613 to 1925 (Box 32, Folder 15)
      - An Island Crisis (Box 32, Folder 16)
      - Moderation (Box 32, Folder 17)
      - Monday Morning to You (Box 32, Folder 18)
      - My Grandfather's Peg Leg (Box 32, Folder 19)
      - The Passing of Amy Lowell, 1925 (Box 32, Folder 20)
      - The Passing of Despair (Box 32, Folder 21)
      - Poetry South (Box 32, Folder 22)
      - The Rise of the New Whaling Industry (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Roman Britain, 1929 (Box 33, Folder 2-3)
      - Santa Claus, Triplets (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Ysleta (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Prefaces, Reviews, and Other Short Works
      - George Ade Obituary, Sigma Chi Newsletter (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - Introduction to a Poe Anthology, Edited By Addison Hibbard, 1927 (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - Jacob Secley, An Epitaph (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - Preface for Bermudiana By Ronald John Williams, 1936 (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - Preface for Julie Eidesheim Book, 1938 (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - Preface for Limited Editions Club (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - Preface for The Gold Bug Edition By Edgar Allen Poe (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - Preface for Lute and Scimitar: Poems and Ballads of Central Asia By Abdullah Achmed, 1927 (Box 33, Folder 13)
      - Preface for Notes of Life and Death By Theodore Morrison, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 14)
      - Preface for The Old House in the Country By Lizette Woodworth Reese, 1936 (Box 33, Folder 15)
      - Preface for Residence in Bermuda (Box 33, Folder 16)
      - Report on Royal America: The Story of Henry Bouquet By G.M. Sassaman, 1943 (Box 33, Folder 17)
      - Review of American Poetry from the Beginning to Whitman By Louis Untermeyer, 1931 (Box 33, Folder 18)
      - Review of Amy Lowell: a chronicle, with extracts from her correspondence By Samuel Foster Damon (Box 33, Folder 19)
      - Review of Broken Ties and Other Stories By Rabinandrath Tagore, 1926 (Box 33, Folder 20)
      - Review of Dark Glory: A Story of Edgar Allan Poe By Dorothy Dow (Box 33, Folder 21)
      - Review of Edgar Allan Poe: A Study in Genius By Joseph Wood Krutch, 1926 (Box 33, Folder 22)
      - Review of The Emily Dickinson Letters By Mabel Loomis Todd, 1929-1931 (Box 33, Folder 23)
      - Review of Emily Dickinson Research Notes, 1929-1931 (Box 33, Folder 24)
      - Review of John Brown's Body By Stephen Vincent Benet, 1923-1924 (Box 33, Folder 25)
      - Review of The Land of the Crooked Tree By Ulysses Prentiss Hedrick, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 26)
      - Review of Little Man What Now? By Hans Fallada, 1934 (Box 33, Folder 27)
      - Review of The Portable Poe Edited By Philip Van Doren Stern (Box 33, Folder 28)
      - Review of Quaker Militant - John Greenleaf Whitter By Albert Mordell, 1933 (Box 33, Folder 29)
      - Review of Sanfelice By Vincent Sheean, 1936 (Box 33, Folder 30)
      - Review of The Sonnets of Petrarch Translated By Joseph Auslander (Box 33, Folder 31)
      - Review of We Can Win This War By W.F. Kernan, 1943 (Box 33, Folder 32)
      - Review of Young Pegasus, Prose and Verse By The Intercollegiate Literary Magazine Conference, 1926 (Box 33, Folder 33)
      - Street Dust and Pollen [Review of Indian Summer; Flame and Dust; The Poets of the Future, A College Anthology; University of Washington Poems, First Series; and Column Poets, 1925 (Box 33, Folder 34)
  - Incomplete/Unidentified Material, 3.
    This subseries includes notes and drafts of incomplete or unidentifiable Allen works. Those that have been identified are arranged and grouped alphabetically while others are arranged according to genre.
    - A-M (Box 34, Folder 1-6)
    - N-Z (Box 34, Folder 7-10)
    - Unidentified Poems (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified Prose (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified/Unknown Prose Material Related to Edgar Allan Poe Work (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Unpublished Material, 1918-1949; 4.
    This material, while some may be incomplete, is much more developed and further along the completion process than material featured in the Incomplete/Unidentified Material subseries. All material in this subseries is titled and may include abstracts, character plots, summaries, and drafts of various Allen unpublished works. Notable is the nascent beginning of a novel, Usted Stanes, set in the future 2015. It was begun October 20th, 1949, just two months before Allen's passing.
    - The Bigger and Better Mr. Peter Polite (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Poems (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Noodin Nanny: A Small Town Story, 1918 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Usted Stanes: Holograph Manuscript, 1949 (Box 35, Folder 4)
- Published Material, 1919-1945; III.
  This series consists of journal and magazine publications of Allen's work. Allen at times published individual poems or serialized installments of his prose in literary journals and commercial magazines such as Cosmopolitan. Note: this series only includes periodical publications and is not an exhaustive representation of Hervey Allen's published works.
  Oversized serial publications are separately housed and can be found in Series XI: Oversized Material, Box 191.
  Hervey Allen's personal library of his published works is cataloged separately and is available by call number in the Special Collections stacks. Please see Special Collections staff for more information.
  - Poetry, 1919-1935; 1.
    This subseries includes Allen's personal copies and/or special editions of his published poetry. Featured are individual poetry submissions to various journal publications. Some material is enclosed in special containers.
    - America's First First, in Theatre Arts Monthly, July 1925 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Belated Spring; Carolina Spring Song; Heart of Night; Shadow to Shadow, in The Yearbook of the Poetry Society of South Carolina, 1921-1924 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Black Roses, in The North American Review, April 1923 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - The Blindman, in The North American Review, December 1919 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - The Bride of Huiltzil: An Aztec Legend, (loose leaf), 1922 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Christmas Coloure, in The Christmas Herald, December 1921 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Confession, in Contemporary Verse, May 1921 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Dead Men: To A Metaphysician, in The Bookman, May 1922 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Despair, in Contemporary Verse, May 1921 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Dream Fragment, in The New Republic, July 1920 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Gargantua and Transfiguration, in The Scholastic, October 1926 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Hylas and Poe in Carolina [article], in The North American Review, October 1920; July 1922 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - La Cloche Joyeuse, The Pitt Review, March 1920 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - The Leaping Poll, in The London Mercury, August 1922 (Box 37, Folder 7)